Hello and welcome. You're watching
Business Today television. I'm Sakshi
Batra and this is what's hot, our latest
offering that discusses the biggest buzz
on the D-Street. Well, of course, we are
in a positive momentum after yesterday's
strong up move on the D-Street. We are
continuing with that momentum as well
today.
So, the Nifty is hovering around 24,285
odd levels. We're up about 0.2% or of
course, not as sharply higher as it was
yesterday, but remember it's also the
day of the Sensex expiry as well. So,
there could be some impact of that. The
mid and the small caps are also into the
green right now. When we look at the key
sectors that are moving in and the key,
you know, indices that are also up, you
know, on the move here. Remember
yesterday it was a large part of IT led
momentum that we saw on the D-Street and
you know, those are the stocks that are
continuing to move up even today, 0.7,
0.8% higher in trade. And when we look
at the other sectors, metals are doing
well today. Financial services are up.
PSU banks, private banks are also up in
trade, but autos have now seen some
pressure build up. You've got oil and
gas and FMCG real estate also seeing
some kind of a selling pressure at this
point in time as well.
Let's also look at the top gainers
within the broadest markets, the Nifty
500 market. You will be able to see
First Source Solutions that's up 15%.
So, there are many stock specific
actions that we are looking at. You have
HDB Financial Services of course after
the earnings. We are seeing a smart move
up on that one. You also have names like
NLC India that's up in trade. You have
LT Rubber, Astec Life Sciences. These
are the names that are truly buzzing as
far as the Nifty 500 names are concerned
and that's how the things are in shape
right now. Let's actually now welcome
our guest on board. We have Mr. Abhishek
Basumallick joining in on the program
with us as a market expert of the day to
share with us a fresh view. Warm welcome
to you, Abhishek ji. Good to have you
with us as always.
Well, you know, how about this how is
the situation panning out now? We've
been reading through on an every week
basis the kind of sentiments that are
changing on the back of statements that
are coming in around West Asia and the
conflict there.
There seems to be an intent to ensure
that this war comes to a conclusion. How
long will that take? Nobody knows at
this point in time,
but at the same time the ceasefire does
not seem to be durable at this point in
time. Concerns around Strait of Hormuz
closure blockade also continue as well.
But it seemed, you know, in the last
couple of sessions where the markets
moved up sharply that the markets
already want to move on beyond this
entire impact of last 5 weeks that we've
seen. How are you sensing the current
trajectory of the markets and what's for
you to watch?
Good morning to you and all your
viewers. I think the the most
encouraging thing that we've seen in in
the last few days when the market moved
up was the participation from the
broader markets. I think the mid caps
and small caps have done particularly
well. I mean, they've held out well
even
probably better than the Nifty and
Sensex stocks. So,
that is always good to see when you have
much more broad-based participation.
Uh
So,
that augurs well for the market. Like
you said,
what happens in the
overall geopolitical scenario is
everybody's guess
and
we are actually one tweet away from
you know, catastrophe once more. We are
we could be one tweet away from
euphoria. So, it it it's just the sort
of sign of times
that no one really knows what's going to
happen
today, tomorrow. That that's true
always, but for now I think the
volatility
or the uncertainty
is is way too much
primarily because of the nature of
you know, how things have been unfolding
specially between
you know, US Iran.
So, at this point in time, Mr.
Basumallick, where are you finding out
some opportunities to start deploying,
you know, cash that's already free to be
deployed? Are you already looking at
some signs that are indicating that now
a turnaround could be right in the
corner and one should take the benefit
of the levels?
Yeah, we have we've been deploying, you
know, cash in our portfolios slowly.
We're sort of nibbling. We've we've
started doing that in the last couple of
weeks.
Uh
One thing is we are now in the earning
season, just getting into the earning
season. So, as and when, you know, for
example, this month goes through, we
will start getting management commentary
and and that is going to give the next
leg up
or down
for the markets. I think downside from
earnings commentary might be limited
because a lot of the bad news would
probably already be baked in.
But
if we hear positive sounds from the
management about how they are seeing the
situation on the ground, then
it helps boost confidence in the
stocks in the sectors that we are
investing in.
Okay.
Let me also
ask you then, how are you looking at the
earnings that are coming in? Is that
micro picture now taking preference over
what's happening externally in making
the decisions as to where should the
money go?
Yeah, of course. I think if you look at
the earnings, so for example, yesterday
we saw earnings coming in from HDB,
particularly, you know, good set of
numbers. So, these are, you know,
indications. It's not that one
particular number is going to determine
everything, but this is just an
indication that uh
earnings from the financial sector could
actually be quite good. So,
you know,
we have to look wait and see for the
other
uh
you know, companies when they come in
with their results, but initial results
are actually quite encouraging from the
companies that have come through.
So, on HDB also let me reiterate for all
our viewers since this stock is sharply
higher in trade today. It opened with
almost 10% gains and right now hovering
around 7% up move. For Q4, HDB Financial
has reported a net profit of 41% surge
at 751 crores. The NII has also improved
by 21 and 1/2% coming in at 2,398
crores. We've also seen that its AUM has
risen to 1.18 lakh crores and the board
has also approved some more borrowing
via debt securities as well.
We have seen, you know, the stock react
positively. It's currently at 690.
Brokerages that have covered the stock,
we have Nomura with a neutral rating at
target price of 740. Jefferies has a
stronger target of 845. They have a buy
rating, whereas Motilal Oswal has a
neutral rating and a 720 target. So, 720
to all the way up to 845 is the range in
which brokerage houses are penciling in
the targets going forward from here.
We had to wait quite a bit after its
listing to really see some momentum
going on the earnings as well as on the
stock price.
Do you think right now is the time that
any fresh investments could be done
looking at some positive indications
from the earnings on HDB?
Uh
I mean, see uh
overall numbers are quite good.
So,
I I mean, it's cost of funds have
declined. So, overall the picture looks
nice. I've not yet gone through in
details whether, you know, merits of,
you know, buy or sell right now, but
overall I think the numbers look quite
good.
Okay. Let me move forward to see some of
the other earnings that have come in and
take your view there as well.
We'll actually see an interesting one.
This one is Tejas Networks that we
wanted to look at today as far as the
earnings are concerned.
You know, for the company, we have seen
that the company has reported a net loss
for the fifth straight quarter and
that's why it makes it important for us
to look at it yet again. Today the stock
is down by 4 and 1/2%. It's of course
among the worst performance in the small
cap index. It's down 47% in the last 1
year already.
EBITDA loss has come in at 118 crores.
Revenue is down 82%. Net loss is at 211
crores versus a loss of 71 crores
reported a year ago in the same quarter.
So, you know, what has gone wrong with
Tejas Networks? I think last year there
was a lot of exuberance around this
stock and a lot of investors, retail
investors, they bet big on the stock on
its way up. And uh since the last 1
year, it's only been a big pain point
for investors. And the earnings also
continue to show a lot of
disappointment. Uh what would you really
analyze here?
So, I mean uh
I I used to track Tejas uh a few years
back. Haven't been tracking it very
closely. Uh
primarily, I think uh you know, because
if I look at their biggest part of the I
mean, at least a large part of the order
book, if I remember correctly, was from
BSNL.
And uh there are always uh you know, a a
delay in payments. And
uh so, the way I think is uh
Tejas was doing the BSNL project more as
a sort of a proof of concept that they
can showcase to the world.
Uh it's it's
its cash flows, its overall growth, etc.
has all been
uh under the radar for quite a while.
So, doesn't honestly merit
uh a look at this point in time. Let it
first prove itself,
uh become profitable, let it be
profitable for a couple of quarters, and
then
uh probably it makes sense to take a
look at it once more.
Okay. Um let's look at another earnings
as well. This one is ICICI Lombard that
we are looking at as well.
Uh we have the earnings that have come
in, a net profit that's improved by 7%
at 547 crores. We've also seen the gross
premium is up by almost 17%. Operating
profit has improved by 31% for the
company at 546 crores. Underwriting
losses stand at 282 crores. However,
combined ratio is at 101.2%
versus 102.5%
here. Uh we have brokerage houses' views
as well. So, we have Goldman Sachs that
has covered the stock with a neutral
rating, a target price of 1965,
higher than what it is currently. Uh
they do believe that the health segment
is definitely leading the company's um
overall profitability.
Uh then JP Morgan's view stands at how
they have upgraded the stock to
outperform now. They've also raised a
target price to 2170.
They believe, of course, that uh
quarterly performance stands strong,
especially retail segments that are now
driving the growth for the company, too.
Uh let's look at the insurance segment
and ICICI Lombard here. Uh what is it as
an opportunity that you would look for?
See, I mean, the two things which has
happened uh in in with ICICI Lombard,
one is that uh
with GST now uh having been removed, uh
pricing has slightly improved. So, that
has helped to an extent.
And it's slowly beginning to gain market
share in both uh
uh motor insurance and commercial
insurance. So, that's something which is
uh looking good. And they're also
bringing in in the health segment that
you talked about, they're bringing in a
lot of product innovations. So, uh
you know, although Indian uh
general insurance market is, you know,
here, I mean, very under penetrated,
primarily uh led by motor insurance,
which is sort of mandatory, and uh
health insurance again, penetration not
very good. So, the opportunity size is
very large, although the growth uh will
probably continue to be in that 18 to
20% uh CAGR for a while. So, overall, a
good franchise, a good uh solid business
to be invested in if one is
uh you know, already invested.
Mm. Okay. But overall on the insurance
space as a whole,
uh where are you finding opportunities?
Uh because we are also looking at what's
uh policy changes that are going to be
uh coming in. That's going to be
something major. We're already looking
at any kind of signs that could further
push the idea of how um you know,
general insurance companies could also
focus on life, life could also focus on
general. So, there are a lot of
opportunities developing. Uh we're
looking at the Bima Sugam as well from
the government as um the
government-owned uh non-commission-based
platform. So, a lot of things are going
to be changing in the months and years
ahead for the insurance space at large.
So, how should an average investor
looking at this um
uh space, you know, pick and choose
certain stocks? How to decide uh which
are the kind of stocks that one should
be really looking at adding?
See, if life and general insurance uh
are allowed to be sold by the same
company, then the obvious beneficiary in
my mind would be LIC. Because uh you
know, just just because of the pure
distribution might that they have, the
agents that they have on the ground. So,
that's going to be and of course, the
the years and the decades of trust that
they've built up with the uh
in the Indian consumer. So, that would
be one leg up. The rest is pretty much
uh I mean, insurance is pretty much a
distribution game. Uh
better uh bancassurance, better
uh distribution puts on the ground,
actually gets you more numbers. So, uh
more or less the the
you know, the the industry is uh
There's no
real innovation that has come out in
terms of products
uh over the last few years. So, uh
a steady-state growth is what I think is
uh what is expected.
Okay, got that. I hope this has also
given you an understanding of how to
really look at the insurance basket at
large. Uh let's also focus on some of
the buzzing pockets today. Um how are
you looking at the metal story develop
since we are still uh in the war zone at
this point in time. And there are still
a lot of questions on uh you know, the
kind of consumption patterns that will
develop from here, the impact on geo uh
you know, the geopolitics as well as on
supply chains. Uh how would you look at
metals really perform going forward?
Yeah, I think if you look at uh
around the world, uh it's an
inflationary environment. And in an
inflationary environment, real assets
tend to do well. So, uh the expectation
is that uh metals, both industrial
metals, as well as uh
you know, as well as
gold, silver, etc. should do well.
Uh
gold, silver may not see
the kind of rise uh that they saw in the
last couple of years. But they can
continue to hold their value. Uh
same uh basically for industrial metals.
Uh
Things like steel, etc. could actually
do uh do well because once this uh you
know, the Middle East war, etc. is over,
you will need a fairly large uh
reconstruction
uh
you know, effort coming in. And that
that could actually put uh
you know, put in a lot of demand for
steel.
Okay. Uh what about uh the IT space? Um
you know, of course, that's the biggest
elephant that one has to really look at.
Um earnings have started to pour in. Uh
for TCS, the indications were largely in
line, no negative surprises. Of course,
TCS is now embroiled in another kind of
um an issue uh that the country is
really looking at.
Uh but um you know, business-wise, the
kind of sentiments that we were seeing
and how more companies will be reporting
their earnings. Wipro is uh scheduled to
report its earnings today. So, the
entire focus will again be on the tech
majors. Uh how are you really looking at
um the opportunity here after the recent
underperformance? Is this a space that
one should start nibbling into? If yes,
then should one be very selective in
choosing the kind of stocks one should
be with at? And uh large caps versus mid
caps, where do you see more
opportunities?
So, I think you know, IT, the the
cycle, down cycle was overdone.
It's not that uh AI is going to just
change the world. I think we would we're
just going through
uh
the the normal cycle where we find
initially a lot of euphoria when a new
technology comes in. Then people start
using it and figure out that it's not as
easy to implement, especially at an
enterprise scale,
uh
all the things that it promises. And
then the euphoria sort of dies down, and
realism kicks in. Right? I think now we
are slowly getting into that stage
where, you know, people are realizing
that AI is going to be an add-on
technology to the existing ones. You
will not be able to replace uh all your
uh you know, enterprise technology with
uh things that uh somebody uh can just
code up on uh over a weekend. So, that's
not going to happen. And even uh
you know, for large systems, you will
need integration, you'll need security.
Uh
What is the most likely going to happen
is that a lot of AI is going to be built
into the
uh you know, or the productivity
benefits are going to be built into the
new contracts, which we are already
seeing happening. So, margins uh will
get squeezed
uh from the from a contract basis. But
that will probably get passed on because
uh you will also see a lot of uh you
know, lot less number of employees that
are going to be required. So,
previously, our entire IT services model
was based on labor arbitrage and
basically head count uh you know, just
just to to
more people and uh
you know, churn more widgets. So, that
is going to change
uh
very quickly and we are now going to see
a lot more of uh
uh
you know, revenue coming in per
employee. So, that's going to change.
So, overall the
you know, the likelihood
of for these large IT companies to
maintain their margins is uh you know,
very very possible. So,
we are already seeing
uh large
uh companies and we
saw Oracle uh doing a large layoff. So,
this is what is going to happen over
time.
The other very big factor that that we
are going to see or we are already
seeing uh maybe it's going to accelerate
is the
you know, growth in GCCs. So, you will
find that a lot of these global
companies
uh figuring out that India ends up being
a lot cheaper and now uh you know, the
productivity benefits etc.
uh with people using uh AI is going to
be
uh very high. So, a lot more of work
moving to the GCCs.
Fair point. So, I hope this is also
given an understanding to viewers as to
how to really look at the scenarios
around IT sector and how to approach it
in case you uh your portfolios are big
on it, then how do you look at it in
case you have still not taken exposure,
how do you look at the evolving
scenarios here? Um another key aspect
that we've been focusing since um last
couple of days is the fact that there is
um another concern that's developing
within the domestic market and that's
with regards to the uh upcoming
monsoons. We've seen the IMD um come up
with a report saying that this year we
could be seeing below normal rainfall.
Uh now, Mr. Basumallick, last four to
five years we've actually seen above
normal monsoons um and you know, things
have turned out to be quite good for the
agri sector as a whole. Uh this time
around these concerns that are
developing, there's an El Nino risk that
is being talked about as well. So,
everybody is talking about how of
course, because of the geopolitical
tensions, we were already at the risk of
higher inflation because of rising crude
oil prices. In case the monsoons also
are not up to the mark, what would that
lead to in terms of uh the agri prices?
What would that lead to the rural
incomes? Uh could that further fuel into
higher inflation and therefore how does
one really approach uh the entire agri,
fertilizer, irrigation space at large?
Usually this is the time right at the
onset of kharif sowing that a lot of
investors start to build in their
positions for uh the agri and fertilizer
related stocks. So, how should one be
really going about it? You could
probably break your answer into two,
give us an understanding on the
macroeconomy impact first and then
probably tell us what to do with the
sectors in question.
So,
you know, obviously
I think last five years we've not had uh
uh a drought-like scenario or or
deficiency in rainfall. So, if it
happens this year, it will be after many
years. And last few times we've had El
Nino, we've actually had uh droughts in
large parts of the country.
And
you know, that's something very
concerning and compounding that concern
this year is actually the uh the
you know, problem with in the Middle
East which is impacting
uh fertilizers, right? Urea uh
uh supply of urea and other fertilizers.
So, these two can actually combine and
create a lot more strain on the agri
economy
and consequently on uh inflation, food
inflation. So, you know, like I keep
saying, in India inflation is dependent
primarily on only two things. One is
food prices and the other is fuel
prices. So, uh you know, with these two
uh
actually
both of these on the uh you know, on the
rise, we could actually see inflation
which we've seen to be very benign over
the last uh you know, year year and a
half
uh actually shoot up to you know, maybe
even higher than the upper band of 4 to
6% that RBI has of their tolerance
level, we could actually see you know, 5
6% inflation in the later half of the
year. So, that's something that we need
to uh keep on our radars.
Uh obviously
wherever you have droughts, you will
uh or or if you have uh agrarian uh
strain,
uh then
it it sort of uh
flows through to the FMCG sector and
other consumer sectors as well.
Uh so, that's something again we'll have
to uh you know,
uh take care of or you know, think
about.
That's primarily and I mean the other
you know, the the other side is uh agri
products. Uh
uh most agri products, the prices will
likely go up. So,
uh if you are uh trading agro
commodities or if the companies where uh
you know, uh
it uh deals with agri products, uh they
could actually see uh some good times.
Okay, got that. So, I hope that this is
also giving you enough and more
understanding. Let's approach the
heavy-weighted uh sectors now, banks
particularly.
Uh what are you looking at here? Uh
private banks vis-a-vis public sector
banks vis-a-vis NBFCs, where is uh the
fresh opportunity emerging?
I think all of them. I think uh you
know, most of uh
most of the large public sector banks
have cleaned up their books. Uh
uh private sector banks are
uh also
you know, last couple of years things
have gotten better. The challenge today
with the banks is uh differentiation.
The challenge is getting CASA because a
large part of the you know, deposit
making
uh has moved over to
uh mutual funds.
So, that that has actually been a
systemic change in
uh in the overall financial markets. So,
increasingly I I I think that you know,
getting CASA, getting growth capital for
banks might be challenging. So,
uh we'll have to consider
uh lower growth rates for banks.
And in the overall space, I think
finance uh NBFCs, MFIs uh probably are
in a better shape today uh
than in the last few years. Uh
most of the
problems are out of the
uh you know, out of the cycle. Things
can do well for maybe the next one year
before uh things uh start becoming
uh iffy again because uh if you look at
MFI, it it goes through very short
cycles of maybe one or two years of good
growth and then uh problems uh start
cropping up. So, we are all probably in
that uh you know, space where things can
do well
uh for the next one year uh before you
start getting concerned once more.
Okay, got that. I hope that this has
also helped uh all our viewers out
there.
Um okay, in the end uh Abhishek, help me
understand. Say if somebody has about 5
lakh rupees to deploy in the current uh
scenario, how would you advise uh that
investor to um you know, use that money,
how to diversify and how to make the
best of the um you know, long-term
strategy right now?
So, I think you know,
uh
I I usually don't uh recommend people
getting in individual stocks
uh if if they don't know what they are
doing. So, the
decent option is to
uh buy a you know, maybe a index fund,
maybe Nifty
uh 500 uh
and just just stagger it over the next
uh you know, five weeks. Just just hold
1 1 lakh uh over the next five weeks and
uh and then
that should take care of the you know,
the
the basic volatility
and uh overall if you are able to get in
at at these levels in the market and if
you are able to hold on for the next two
three years, uh my sense is that you
will make decent returns out of this.
Okay, I hope that this has also given
you an understanding of where should the
fresh money flow in. Thank you so much,
Abhishek, for being with us and sharing
all your thoughts across the pockets
that we've discussed today. Always a
pleasure. Thank you. Thank you.
All right, viewers, we are inching
slightly higher up now, 24,300 onto the
Nifty, 3/10% up in trade. Let's see how
things pan out as we approach the half
time as well. Uh it's a mixed trend as
far as the sectors are concerned. You do
have metals, financial services, IT,
banks, broader markets that are up and
about. Just the pockets of auto, realty,
and FMCG that are slightly on the lower
end at this point in time. But the
advance-decline ratio is towards the
positive as well. Let's see whether key
we can further pick up some momentum as
we approach half time and into the
second half. But remember, because of
the weekly expiry, there could be some
volatile moves as well. So, stay tuned
with us onto Business Today Television
as we track the markets completely for
you. And in case you have any queries
about the stocks in your portfolio, ask
them away at 12:00 noon show, that's
Daily Calls. I'll be back for that.
The government claims that this
expressway is going to cut the travel
time up between uh Delhi and Dehradun by
more than a half.
So, how true is this claim? To find out,
we have now decided to travel
Dehradun.